<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Adam Byram]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-07T21:10:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.adambyram.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Byram]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goals for 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/01/goals-for-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/01/goals-for-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's that time of year again.  These goals will change over the course of the year, but today, my goals for 2012 are to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pay off cat medical debt</li>
<li>Sell (or rent) house</li>
<li>Launch at least one new iOS game or app</li>
<li>Get involved with open source</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, the standard goals of lose weight, eat better, save more, and the like are all things I plan to work on as well.  The goals above are specific to 2012.  It should be a fun &amp; exciting year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Back on 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/looking-back-on-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T19:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/looking-back-on-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2011 was a crazy year for me.  It was a year full of change.  This year I:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Started dating my beautiful girlfriend</p></li>
<li><p>Watched the last launch of Space Shuttle Discovery from the NASA press site thanks to the STS-133 NASATweetup</p></li>
<li><p>Took a great vacation to Charleston, SC</p></li>
<li><p>Turned 30</p></li>
<li><p>Moved 2200 miles from the East Coast to the West Coast for a new job</p></li>
<li><p>Began working a dream job in the space industry</p></li>
</ul>


<p>There were some low points in 2011, but overall, it's been a good year.  In a lot of ways, I feel like 2011 was a transitional year.  All of the change is mostly finished at this point, so it feels like it's time for the good stuff to begin.  I'm <em>really</em> excited about 2012 - I think like it's going to be an amazing year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/11/26/blog-block/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-26T01:28:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/11/26/blog-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really thought I'd have a lot to blog about since this whole week was a
pretty crazy cross country adventure...but I can't seem to focus on blogging
at the moment.  I don't know if it's just a writer's block thing or what.
Whenever I sit down to write, I keep thinking I'm writing out some formal
document and that ends up causing me to keep thinking about it and then I just
stop.  My goal is to blog <em>more</em> now that I'm out in LA and I have lots of
friends around the country that will probably be interested in updates.  At
this point, I'm not sure what I'm going to do.  I thought about just using
Tumblr instead of my own custom WordPress install or I may simply start fresh
with this domain.  I'll definitely find a way to send out updates on my LA
adventure, but it looks like it'll be a little bit longer.</p>

<p>One quick update though - I did make it to LA just fine and both kitties made
it smoothly.  My furniture isn't here yet, so my apartment is basically empty
at the moment, but at least I'm here.  I'll post more in the near future, but
so far, so good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[T-0]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/10/28/t-0/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-28T21:09:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/10/28/t-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is my last day of work on the East Coast. It's a sad day since I'm
leaving a stable company full of good people and interesting opportunities. At
the same time, it's an exciting day since I'm leaving so I can prepare myself
for the 2200 mile move to Los Angeles before I start my dream job of building
spaceships. I never thought I'd be trading my reasonably large house in
Tennessee and basically all of my stuff for a tiny one bedroom apartment in
LA, but I never thought I'd be able to work on spaceships either.</p>

<p>I got a great send off from my coworkers. A few of them decided to do a little
decorating to my cube...</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0017.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0017.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>...and my car...</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0024.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0024.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>...but the best part was the cupcake. :)</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0021.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0021.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goals - 2011 Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/01/03/goals-2011-edition/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-03T20:07:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/01/03/goals-2011-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year, I'm setting 5 major goals for myself. I have several other
behaviors to change/actions to take this year, but I'm only considering these
five items my goals since they are realistic, actionable, and measurable.</p>

<h3>Release a new app or website</h3>

<p>I've been working on several ideas over the last year or so and I'm going to
really push to get at least one new project released publicly. I'm not going
to be more specific other than the new "thing" will must be something anyone
can sign up for or download. Open source, closed source, free, or paid -
doesn't matter - I just want to complete v1.0 of a new project.</p>

<h3>Max out 401K &amp; Roth IRA</h3>

<p>Pretty simple - $16,500 pre-tax dollars into the 401K and $5,000 of after-tax
dollars into a Roth IRA.</p>

<h3>Lose weight</h3>

<p>Nothing special about this goal. I'm targeting 35 pounds lost by the end of
the year. I've had this one on my goal list for a while, so it's time to
finally knock this one off.</p>

<h3>Write a journal entry a day</h3>

<p>This is a new one for me. I wanted to do a 365 photo project, but I'd really
like to do more writing...so a 365 writing project it is. I won't be
publishing these, but I'm really enjoying it so far (even though I'm only 3
days in).</p>

<p>2011 feels different from years past, so I have pretty high hopes for
accomplishing these goals (as well as several other things).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
