<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Adam Byram]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-07T21:42:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.adambyram.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Byram]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Thoughts on the Surface Pro]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2013/03/09/my-thoughts-on-the-surface-pro/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T21:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2013/03/09/my-thoughts-on-the-surface-pro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that I’ve had a week and a half of real world use with the Surface Pro, I thought I’d share my observations.</p>

<p>The TL;DR version is that I feel like The Verge’s <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/2/5/3955130/microsoft-surface-pro-review">review</a> was spot on and at the end of the day, the device had too many compromises for me to justify the price tag.  It’s a well made device with lots of potential, but that potential isn’t realized today.</p>

<h3>My Priorities</h3>

<p>I had (and loved) my Acer convertible TabletPC back in 2004/2005.  It was perfect for college when combined with OneNote.  I really want something just as useful today for taking notes, doing some diagraming/whiteboarding, basic sketching, and photo editing.  The pen was great back then, but multi touch was missing.  A pen combined with multi touch technology seems like it would make an excellent note taking device and that was my main driver with the Surface Pro.</p>

<p>As a secondary benefit, it would be nice to have a Windows development machine that is portable, yet powerful enough to handle any tasks I need.  I have a Windows 8 desktop and I have a 17” MacBook Pro that has a Windows 8 boot camp partition, but neither of those are really as portable as I would want.  I’m mostly an iOS developer these days, so this feature isn’t critical, but it’s certainly a nice to have.</p>

<p>Finally, it would be great if I could play most of my Steam games (even on low settings).  I’m not usually at my Windows desktop most of the day, but it’d be nice to be able to pop in and play a little Borderlands or Diablo 3 without having to be tied to my office machine.  This is a very low priority, but I’d be another nice to have.</p>

<h3>Initial Impression</h3>

<p>The Surface Pro looks and feels really nice.  The build quality is excellent.  The pen is the only component that feels a little cheaper, but it’s a light tube of shiny black plastic compared to the solid slab of metal and glass.  The screen is bright, vibrant, and clear.  I&rsquo;m not a fan of the 16:9 aspect ratio, but  most people don&rsquo;t seem to mind it.  The out of the box setup is fast and simple &ndash; I think it actually had less setup steps than my iPad which is impressive from Microsoft.</p>

<p>The kickstand is solid and the USB 3.0 port is blazing fast (if you have a good USB drive).  The kickstand is nice and works excellently when propping the device on the counter to watch Netflix while cooking.  It works great in laptop mode on a solid surface, but it’s hit or miss when using it as a laptop on your lap.  It works, but I had to keep fiddling with it to get it to balance properly and to get the screen at a good viewing angle.</p>

<p>Overall, the Surface Pro is a very impressive package.</p>

<h3>Type Cover</h3>

<p>Since I knew I’d be using it as a laptop whenever I wasn’t taking notes, I picked up a Type Cover.  The Type Cover is one of the best tablet keyboards I’ve used.  It took about an hour for me to adjust to it, but after that, it felt great.  The magnetic connector is very secure and I had no concerns about it sliding off in my backpack like my iPad’s Logitech Ultra-thin Keyboard does.  The trackpad area is very responsive, but it’s so small, it’s unusable unless you’re in a pinch.</p>

<p>The big downside is that the keyboard has some serious responsiveness issues if you use it on your lap or any other non-solid surface.  I would randomly experience ignored key-presses &ndash; not just once or twice, but nearly half the time.  I’d have to press the key 3 or 4 times to get it to register the key press.  The keyboard was barely flexed, but I never experienced this when using it on a solid surface.</p>

<p>At $130 on top of the Surface Pro’s price, it’s not a cheap cover at all, but to me, this is a must have if you buy a Surface or Surface Pro and expect to do any decent amount of typing.</p>

<h3>The Pen</h3>

<p>The pen is really well done.  It’s Wacom tech, which means it’s very accurate and there is zero noticeable lag between pen movement and when the “ink” shows up on the screen.  It has great pressure sensitivity and feels like a ballpoint pen in your hand.  I really wish Microsoft included a slot for the pen.</p>

<p>The pen magnetically connects to the device via the power port.  That means you have to leave your pen on the table while you charge the Surface Pro.  I was constantly checking the pen when I was carrying the tablet to meetings &ndash; the connector magnets are strong, but depending on how you hold the tablet, it’s really easy to knock the pen off and never notice it’s lost.  This was particularly a problem for me when I would pick the tablet up.  The pen never detached while it my backpack, but it would nearly always detach when I picked up the tablet from the side (usually when I was pulling it out of my backpack).</p>

<p>In use, the pen worked great &ndash; particularly with OneNote 2013.  I wish there was a little texture on the screen of the Surface Pro so there was a little bit of resistance, but I’m sure that would impact the quality of the display in other ways.  The pen is every bit as good as I was expecting.</p>

<h3>Tablet Mode</h3>

<p>I know it’s not a big surprise to anyone, but there is still no ecosystem of Windows 8 touch interface apps.  I found a few third party apps (Stacks for Instapaper &amp; Nextgen Reader come to mind) that were nice.  The Netflix app was excellent &ndash; it’s probably the best implementation of Netflix I’ve seen on any device.  Outside of that, I found the app selection to be really, really lacking.</p>

<p>Microsoft has plenty of their own apps for calendaring, email, address book, etc.  All of these apps work, but they are about as basic as you can get.  I’m actually OK with basic for the most part, but Microsoft decided not to support CardDAV and CalDAV protocols in the contacts app and calendar app respectively.  That essentially means I can’t access any of my Google contact or calendar data out of the box.  It turns out, you can go to live.com and in an obscure mean, you can link your Google contacts to your live.com account and gain access that way.  For calendaring, you can import an iCal feed from the live.com site, but it’s a one way, one time import which is pretty much pointless for me since I can’t see my current Google calendar let alone update it.</p>

<p>When I was using the tablet mode apps, the charms and multitouch gestures work well for the most part.  The charms make a heck of a lot more sense when using them with touch vs a mouse on my Windows 8 desktop.  I love the share charm.  It makes a ton of sense when apps implement it properly and I genuinely hope something like this is implemented on iOS and Android in the future.  I had some trouble moving tiles on the desktop &ndash; sometimes it would think I’m was trying to scroll, sometimes it would select the tile, and sometimes it would move the tile.  Overall, the experience using the touch interface was very positive, but there just aren’t any apps to use there and Microsoft needs to step up their game with their built-in apps &ndash; both in features and interoperability with other services (specifically Google accounts).</p>

<p>One day in the future, the tablet experience on a Windows 8 device may be excellent.  The hardware is very responsive overall, but the software needs polish.  The biggest deal breaker though is that beyond Kindle, Netflix, and a few other apps, you simply can’t find any apps worth using in tablet mode.</p>

<h3>Desktop Mode</h3>

<p>The desktop runs extremely smoothly and everything is very snappy thanks to the SSD.  I loaded Visual Studio, SQL Server, Resharper, Lightroom, Sketchbook Pro, Chrome, and several other apps that are essential for me.  I also installed the Office 365 trial &ndash; mainly because I wanted OneNote 2013.</p>

<p>Since Windows doesn’t natively support high density displays and the Surface Pro has a high density display, Windows is set by default to scale the desktop by 150%.  The impact of this is that everything on the screen is magnified so icons are reasonably touchable and most system text (menu bars, etc) is readable.  In this mode, all of the Microsoft developed apps run great and look really sharp.</p>

<p>Third party apps, (Chrome most notably), were a blur fest.  Text was muddy looking and touch detection seemed really flaky.  Links wouldn’t activate when I tapped them and Chrome generally acted funny.  Sketchbook Pro worked well, particularly with the pen, but it doesn’t support pinch to zoom &ndash; you still have to get a zoom tool from the menu bar if you want to pan &amp; zoom and that’s unfortunate.  Lightroom ran fine, but it was almost impossible to use the interface via touch.  Using a mouse or the Type Cover’s touchpad generally worked fine with these apps even with scaling turned on.  I know the Surface Pro is new, but Windows 8’s touch features have been available to developers for quite a while &ndash; so I’m curious if third party support will improve.</p>

<p>When I connected my external monitor via mini DisplayPort, everything was blurry &ndash; scaling was applied to it as well even though it didn’t need the scaling.  I disabled desktop scaling and that solved the external monitor issues and made Chrome look &amp; act normal, but that caused all system text and icons to become super tiny.  Using desktop mode with scaling turned off was quite a challenge &ndash; ideally, third party apps will be updated to properly work with scaling turned on and to incorporate the new touch API, but I didn’t find a single non-Microsoft app that I use which did that today.</p>

<h3>Gaming</h3>

<p>For my purposes, this wasn’t critical at all, but I wanted to give it a try so I installed Borderlands 2 and Diablo 3.  Borderlands 2 never really ran properly for me.  I couldn’t actually select any of the menu items once I got to the game’s main menu.  I think this had to do with the desktop scaling, but I didn’t try again after I disabled scaling.  The main menu was having trouble rendering at a reasonable rate, so I didn’t have high hopes.</p>

<p>Diablo 3 actually ran nicely.  I used a Microsoft Wedge Touch mouse instead of the trackpad on the Type Cover and it was definitely playable.  At 1080p, the game stuttered quite a bit even with no enemies on the screen, but dropping the resolution to 720p made things run smoothly.  The Surface Pro definitely got very, very warm to the touch (particularly on the top of the unit) and the fans kicked into high gear, but they were still much more quiet than my MacBook Pro’s fans.  Diablo looked really nice on the display even though it wasn’t running at full resolution.</p>

<h3>Overall Thoughts</h3>

<p>My main use case was taking notes and sketches.  When doing that, the tablet works well.  Navigating OneNote 2013 could be much better though.  It’s still a desktop interface designed for a mouse (e.g. you still open up the ribbon menu to get different pen colors, line widths, etc), but once you’re just writing (and not creating a new page, changing pen color, etc) things are good.</p>

<p>The most disappointing thing is that OneNote 2013 feels very much like the original version of OneNote I used on my original TabletPC.  As far as ink support and handwriting recognition, that’s a good thing, but it’s very disappointing to see the interface wasn’t updated for touch use.  It’s also worth noting that the OneNote app for iOS can’t display ink &ndash; it just displays “[ink]” anywhere you wrote with the pen&hellip;making my notes useless there.  The OneNote web interface does display ink, but my ink was almost unreadable on the web.  Ink that was totally readable and regular size on the tablet looked 2x as large on the web and there was no way to zoom out.</p>

<p>I’m really disappointed with the support for 3rd party apps.  Specifically Sketchbook Pro 6 and Lightroom 4.  Sketchbook handles the pen just fine, but I was really expecting to be able to use pan &amp; zoom via touch since that’s available on every other platform.  Lightroom was disappointing &ndash; it ran very fast, but without a mouse, it just wasn’t usable on the Surface Pro’s screen.  I realize these issues aren’t within Microsoft’s control, but they they definitely impact the value I received from Microsoft’s platform.</p>

<p>My biggest worry is the battery life.  I get 3-4 hours with reasonably light use.  The battery connector is proprietary and needs to be plugged into the wall &ndash; you won’t be charging this off of another PC’s USB port.  The power brick is smallish, but it’s something that has to stay in my backpack constantly.  If I forget to charge the tablet overnight, there is a good chance I’ll have to plug it up as soon as I get to the office to make sure I have enough juice to make it through a few hour long meetings.  I’m used to having my iPad battery last days without worrying about it and for something I need regularly, I really wish I had more than 3-4 hours of power&hellip;or at the very least, I wish I could trickle charge it off other nearby computers.</p>

<p>The tablet mode has tons of potential and was a nice experience, but until there are many, many more quality apps, it’s an experience that no one will see.  The desktop mode is functional, but I don’t understand why the device has a high density display when Windows clearly isn’t meant to run on one and it’s extremely obvious as soon as any non-Microsoft app is launched.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, I can’t see myself reaching for the Surface Pro instead of my iPad when I have tablet type tasks to do.  I also can’t see myself reaching for it over my MacBook Pro when I’m at home and need to do more desktop type tasks.  It’s definitely the best device I have for note taking, but due to the really limited battery and several smaller issues, I don’t feel that I can count on it always being ready to go when I need it for note taking.</p>

<p>I’m not set on having one single device that can support all three of these scenarios, so I’m ok using three different devices.  The catch is my iPad is <em>really</em> great at being a tablet, my MacBook Pro is <em>really</em> great at being a Mac/PC, but my Surface Pro is only moderately good at being a note taking device outside of the excellent pen support &ndash; it’s just a very clunky, disjointed experience and I’m not sure I want to deal with that.  There are many good ideas spread across the hardware and software of the Surface Pro, but I don’t feel Microsoft has found a way to combine those pockets of good ideas into a compellingly useful product just yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cat Feeder Project - Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/21/cat-feeder-project-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T14:47:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/21/cat-feeder-project-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent some time this weekend working on the hardware to provide cooling for the cat feeder.  The goal is to get the cat feeder to the same temperatures as a refridgerator.  I want to keep the unit as trouble free and cost effective as possible, so I don&rsquo;t want to go the compressor route.  The option I&rsquo;m prototyping is using a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermoelectric_cooling">thermoelectric cooling (TEC)</a> chip (known as a Peltier element).  If you apply power to a TEC, it will cool on one side and heat on another.  If you&rsquo;re trying to cool, you have to remove the heat from the hot side of the TEC with an external heatsink.  TECs are very inefficient, but they should be able to do exactly what I need for this project.</p>

<h2>The Prototype Setup</h2>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2012-10-21-cat-feeder-project-part-2/Cooling-Test.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2012-10-21-cat-feeder-project-part-2/Cooling-Test.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h3>Components</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/50">Arduino Uno R3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/184">Adafruit Adjustable Breadboard Power Supply</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/798">12V 1A Regulated Power Adapter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10213">2 x N-Channel MOSFET 60V 30A</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10686">70mm Heatsink and Fan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10080">40mm x 40mm Peltier element</a></li>
<li>Breadboards, jumper wires, heatsink compound, and a few push buttons</li>
</ul>


<h3>Assembly</h3>

<p>I used a few push buttons on the breadboard next the to Arduino so I could control the power to the heatsink&rsquo;s fan and the TEC.  The Arudino&rsquo;s PWM output is sent to the two MOSFETs which varies the amount of current sent to the fan &amp; TEC.  The fan &amp; TEC are both connected to the 12V 1A regulated power supply via the Adafruit breadboard power supply.  I originally tried to run the TEC at a lower voltage than 12V by using the adjustable power supply, but it turned out to be easier to just hook both items directly to the 12V supply.</p>

<h3>Results</h3>

<p>The power supply can&rsquo;t provide enough power to run the TEC with the MOSFET wide open.  One the TEC starts drawing a reasonable amount of power, the fan starts slowing down and evetually, the TEC will draw so much current that everything else shuts down.  I was able to run the fan with the MOSFET wide open and the TEC MOSFET set to about 67% power.  At those settings, the fan runs (at less than full speed) and the TEC is able to cool quite reasonably.  The TEC MOSFET started getting quite hot, so I added a passive heatsink on there.</p>

<p>The at the end of the day, I was able to use the settings above to take the TEC from 75F down to 38F in just a few seconds.  I ran the whole setup in this configuration for about 5 minutes with no issues.  Overall, I&rsquo;m very happy to get near freezing temperatures with the relatively small power supply.</p>

<h3>Next Steps</h3>

<p>I want to get a bigger power supply.  I&rsquo;d really like to get an adjustable lab power supply so I could try different amounts of current to see what exactly I need, but I&rsquo;m thinking I&rsquo;ll try a 12V 2A power supply.  I need to see how much current I can run through the jumper wires if I upgrade the power.  The current test didn&rsquo;t get the wires hot, but I&rsquo;m not sure how much more current they&rsquo;ll take.</p>

<p>At this point, I just need to get the TEC a little cooler while getting the fan to run faster on the heatsink.  I&rsquo;m not too worried about the hinksink though&hellip;it never got that hot even with the fan running slower.  I&rsquo;d like to build a small enclosure so I can experiment with cooling air and not just the surface of the TEC.  This will probably mean I end up building a styrofoam box (or buying one) and mounting a heatsink &amp; fan on the cold side of the TEC to distribute the cooling power.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early Thoughts on Microsoft Surface]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/17/early-thoughts-on-microsoft-surface/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T19:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/17/early-thoughts-on-microsoft-surface</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The short version: I’m not going to buy one and I’m not sure why most people would buy one at launch.</p>

<p>So the Surface pricing was revealed as the <a href="http://surface.microsoftstore.com/store/msstore/Content/pbpage.Surface?ESICaching=off">pre-order page</a> went live on the Microsoft Store.  For $499 you get a 32GB tablet without a keyboard.  Add $100 and you get a touch cover keyboard with it.  Lets be clear here, you’re going to want the keyboard.  Yes, it’s designed around touch, but Office is one of the bigger selling points of this tablet and you’re going to want a keyboard.</p>

<p>Assuming you go with the $599 tablet + keyboard combo, what do you get?</p>

<p>Well, you get&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>Windows RT</li>
<li>Office Home &amp; Student 2013 RT</li>
<li>Sleek (presumably high build quality) tablet hardware</li>
<li>An innovative cover / keyboard combo</li>
</ul>


<p>That’s fine and dandy, but the real question is what can you <strong>do</strong> with that setup&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>Run the basic first party apps on all mobile platforms like Mail, Calendar, Contacts, Web Browser, etc.</li>
<li>Run the big hitter 3rd party apps on all mobile platforms like Netflix, Kindle, Evernote, etc.</li>
<li>Run Office (specifically Word, PowerPoint, Excel, and OneNote)</li>
</ul>


<p>If you don’t see what you do 90% of the time in that list, you’re going to be a bit screwed if you pick up a Surface at launch.  Since this is Windows RT and not Windows 8, it looks the same on the surface, but you can’t actually run any of your regular Windows desktop apps.  Office doesn’t include apps you may expect like Outlook, nor does it allow you to use certain features like macros&hellip;which may or may not be a deal breaker depending on your use case.  All apps have to come through the Windows Store as well &ndash; this is more like Apple’s iOS than it is the traditional Windows you’re probably expecting.</p>

<p>Sure, there is an a Windows Store for apps now&hellip;but you’re going to be <strong>very</strong> disappointed with the selection if it doesn’t improve drastically between now and the official launch in 10 days.  Last I checked, there were 663 games in the store.  Of those games, you’ve probably heard of 5 or so of them&hellip;I wouldn’t expect much from the rest.  All of the other categories are worse.  Take the Finance category &ndash; there are 46 apps total.  Of those 46, 3 are checkbook/budget apps, a couple are currency converters, and the rest are basically stock tickers.  You’ll see a few apps like Adobe Lightroom 4, but then you’ll see they are “Desktop Apps” which means they aren’t going to work on your Surface.</p>

<p>After browsing through every category in the store, there just isn’t much substance there.  I really thought there would be more useful and/or fun apps at this point, but honestly, I have no idea what people are going to use on their $600 tablet other than the big apps I mentioned earlier.  If Office on a tablet is <strong>that</strong> important to you (and you can live with the Office RT limitations), then maybe this tablet makes a sense for you.  Otherwise, you can get the other apps on a device like the Nexus 7 for much cheaper without sacrificing much (if anything).</p>

<p>The worst part of this is the fact that the hardware looks really nice, the battery life sounds like it’s very reasonable, and the hardware specs overall are certainly capable of delivering some compelling experiences.  Those experiences just don’t exist in the Windows Store today.  I’m afraid the first wave of consumers will pick up the Surface, realize their tablet isn’t backed by a meaningful number of quality apps, and promptly kill any momentum the Surface picks up at launch.  Even the version of Office 2013 that ships on the Surface is a “Preview” release&hellip;it’s not even finished yet (although it may be perfectly usable as is &ndash; who knows).</p>

<p>All in all, I hope Microsoft can pull this one off, but I’m not sure their massive marketing campaign can make up for the lackluster launch lineup once consumers get their shiny new devices home.  It’ll be a shame to see such a beautiful hardware design go to waste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cat Feeder Project - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/12/cat-feeder-project-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-12T23:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/12/cat-feeder-project-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some of you may know my cat situation.  If you&rsquo;re not aware, the long and the short of it is that my cats used to only eat dry cat food.  One of the cats ended up getting very sick when I moved to Los Angeles.  After she recovered (she&rsquo;s fine now), she decided she&rsquo;ll never eat dry food again and only eats very specific wet cat food.</p>

<p>The problem is that I have two very nice automated dry food feeders that I can&rsquo;t use.  Both cats need to be on a schedule to help control their weight.  So I started researching wet cat food feeders and it turns out, there aren&rsquo;t many.  Not only that, the feeders that are out there all use ice packs which limit you to 8 or maybe 12 hours of feeding.  That&rsquo;s totally not acceptable to me so I&rsquo;ve decided I&rsquo;m going to try to design my own wet cat food feeder.</p>

<h3>What</h3>

<p>So what is this thing?  Well, it&rsquo;s a small (~2 ft wide) unit that has a certain number of rotating food cups.  The food cups can be filled with wet food (or dry food) and the unit can be programmed to expose each food cup to the cats on a specific schedule.  The unexposed food will stay seal up inside the unit and a cooling unit will keep the unexposed food nice and cool.</p>

<p>The goal is to have the unit keep food at refridgerated temperatures (TBD what that means) consistently to allow food to be stored in the unit for up to three days.  That seems to be the maximum time wet food is allowed to be refridgerated based on manufacturer information, so that&rsquo;ll be the target for version 1.</p>

<p>If the machine can feed twice a day for an overnight trip or once a day for a long weekend trip, it&rsquo;ll be fantastic, so that&rsquo;s the target.</p>

<h3>Why</h3>

<p>On top of the issues mentioned above, I really want a exposure to the hardware + software world.  I&rsquo;ve worked on software for quite a long time and basically everything I&rsquo;ve built is totally virtual in nature.  That&rsquo;s all fine and good, but I&rsquo;m really wanting build something physical.  Of course, some software will still be needed, but I&rsquo;ll also get some electrical engineering, product design, and CAD modeling.</p>

<p>The other part of the why is that I really want to be able to go on a long weekend trip and not have to worry about the cats getting fed.  Today, we basically can&rsquo;t be gone for longer than about 8 hours at a time without having someone come by to feed the cats.</p>

<h3>How</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m planning on building everything with some pretty common parts.  The initial design / prototype is going to be all plastic, mainly because I&rsquo;m getting a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/2105227104/ultra-bot-3d-printer">3D printer</a> in December.  The general electronics won&rsquo;t be anything super special.  For the prototype, I&rsquo;ll be using an Arduino Uno for overall control, a motor controller board to rotate the food dish, a external power module to power the cooling system, and a few other random bits.</p>

<p>For cooling, I&rsquo;m planning on using a Peltier cooler.  They aren&rsquo;t very efficient, but they are relatively easy to use and they can work reasonably well (based on my experience with a little mini fridge).  They are also pretty cheap, so it&rsquo;s quite cost effective from a component perspective.  The cooling will be the trickiest aspect of the whole project.</p>

<h3>When</h3>

<p>Well, I&rsquo;ve already started playing with the basic components and working on the hardware design (the body of the feeder, not the electronic components).  The 3D printer won&rsquo;t be available until later in December, so I can&rsquo;t start working on the real prototype until then, but I&rsquo;ll be able to play with the cooling system this month and into November.  My goal is to have a really rough 3D model ready by the time the printer is available.  I&rsquo;m assuming I&rsquo;ll needed lots of revisions to the plastic parts since all of this (the design process, printing process, and design software) is new to me, but I want to be able to hit the ground running.</p>

<p>As far as the finished product, I&rsquo;m hoping to have a totally working prototype in Q1 2013.  Will that happen? I have no idea, but I really, really want this product so I&rsquo;d like to have something working sooner rather than later.</p>

<h3>What&rsquo;s Next</h3>

<p>I plan to blog my progress on this project.  It&rsquo;s as much for me to keep track of things as it is for everyone else to follow along.  Next time, I&rsquo;ll show the current stage of the design and share some thoughts on the design process as well as the design software I&rsquo;m using.  This should be a fun project, so I hope you have as much fun following along as I&rsquo;m having building this thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on the 13&quot; MacBook Air]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/05/thoughts-on-the-13-macbook-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T21:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/05/thoughts-on-the-13-macbook-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve had my 13&#8221; MacBook Air (mid-2011 model) for a few weeks now and thought it&rsquo;d be a good idea to share my impressions.  I originally moved to Apple on a black MacBook, then switched to a top end 17&#8221; MacBook Pro, and now I&rsquo;m on an Air.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s Good?</h2>

<p><strong>Weight</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s fantastically light.  My MacBook Pro feels like a brick after using the MBA for a while.</p>

<p><strong>Size</strong></p>

<p>Not only is it light, it&rsquo;s thin.  Like, really thin.  It&rsquo;s not really that much thicker than my iPad and that&rsquo;s impressive when you consider it&rsquo;s a full featured computer.</p>

<p><strong>Battery Life</strong></p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t used it for photo/video editing nor have I used it for games, so my usage is pretty moderate, but still, the battery life is excellent.  My MacBook Pro has a good battery life for its size, but the Air has been really impressive.  I haven&rsquo;t timed the battery life, but I can say that I frequently use it for extended periods of time without even thinking about the power cable.  That hasn&rsquo;t been my experience with other laptops (Apple or otherwise).</p>

<p><strong>Solid State Drive</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s amazing how much of a difference a solid state drive makes.  Startup is extremely fast, launching apps is even faster, and even development in a virtual machine is faster.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s Bad?</h2>

<p><strong>Screen Size</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s totally usable for most of my everyday tasks, but for things like development, it&rsquo;s a bit small.  The good news is that it powers an external monitor just fine.  If you&rsquo;re on the go and need to do certain kinds of tasks, it&rsquo;ll feel a bit cramped.  I can&rsquo;t imagine the MacBook Airs line won&rsquo;t merge with the MacBook Pro line to provide the larger screen sizes in the future.</p>

<h2>Other Thoughts</h2>

<p>That&rsquo;s actually the only negative thing I&rsquo;ve noticed.  I happen to have the 4GB RAM/256GB SSD model, so it&rsquo;s maxed out on the basic specs.  It&rsquo;d be nice if the RAM went up to 8GB, but honestly, 4GB has been plenty (even with large-ish databases loaded) due to the SSD.  The storage space may end up being a problem for me down the road if I started storing my main photo library, but I&rsquo;m undecided how I want to handle that.  Overall, the MacBook Air is the best laptop I&rsquo;ve used for my everyday tasks.  I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll find a few things where I miss the power of my PC workstation or my MacBook Pro, but so far, I&rsquo;ve really impressed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goals for 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/01/goals-for-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/01/goals-for-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s that time of year again.  These goals will change over the course of the year, but today, my goals for 2012 are to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pay off cat medical debt</li>
<li>Sell (or rent) house</li>
<li>Launch at least one new iOS game or app</li>
<li>Get involved with open source</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, the standard goals of lose weight, eat better, save more, and the like are all things I plan to work on as well.  The goals above are specific to 2012.  It should be a fun &amp; exciting year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/switching-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T19:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/switching-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been looking into Octopress for a month or so now and I finally decided to take the plunge.  As of now, this blog is now powered by Octopress (more or less out of the box) instead of WordPress.  I&rsquo;d like to change the theme a bit, but it&rsquo;s good enough that I&rsquo;ll leave it for now.</p>

<h3>WordPress &ndash;> Octopress</h3>

<p>Nothing was wrong with WordPress itself, but I just didn&rsquo;t use any of the features it offered.  I&rsquo;d rather just type the blog posts in a regular editor instead of a textbox on a webpage.  There are some great tools out there that help with that of course, but I just don&rsquo;t need the features there either.  In addition, maintaining WordPress means logging in pretty often to check for updates, apply them, make sure the database is backed up, etc.  All of that would be just fine if I received enough benefit to offset the time there, but I just didn&rsquo;t.</p>

<h3>Enter Heroku</h3>

<p>In addition to switching the blogging engine, I moved the physical blog from Linode over to Heroku + Amazon S3.  My blog is very low traffic, so I don&rsquo;t need a high powered VPS host that I have to maintain &amp; patch.  Heroku offers a free account if you don&rsquo;t need much power and can live without a database (well, effectively without a DB &ndash; a 5MB one is included).  I decided to go ahead and put any post specific images/files onto S3 since Heroku offers a limited amount of local storage and I can also redeploy back to Linode if something doesn&rsquo;t work out at Heroku.  For the record though, I <em>love</em> Linode for a Linux VPS host.  I highly recommend them as long as you&rsquo;re comfortable dealing with Linux via the command line.</p>

<h3>Simplicity</h3>

<p>As I get older, the technology side of things appeals to me less and less.  I still love technology in general, but the nitty gritty details of what platform/framework/OS/whatever is the best is less and less interesting to me.  I&rsquo;m more interested in the best way to deliver a solution in a way that is as simple as possible.  That doesn&rsquo;t mean I&rsquo;m adverse to complexity under the hood though. It means I value the experience, productivity, and the ability to simply get things done over the technical aspects of a solution.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Back on 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/looking-back-on-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T19:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/looking-back-on-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2011 was a crazy year for me.  It was a year full of change.  This year I:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Started dating my beautiful girlfriend</p></li>
<li><p>Watched the last launch of Space Shuttle Discovery from the NASA press site thanks to the STS-133 NASATweetup</p></li>
<li><p>Took a great vacation to Charleston, SC</p></li>
<li><p>Turned 30</p></li>
<li><p>Moved 2200 miles from the East Coast to the West Coast for a new job</p></li>
<li><p>Began working a dream job in the space industry</p></li>
</ul>


<p>There were some low points in 2011, but overall, it&rsquo;s been a good year.  In a lot of ways, I feel like 2011 was a transitional year.  All of the change is mostly finished at this point, so it feels like it&rsquo;s time for the good stuff to begin.  I&rsquo;m <em>really</em> excited about 2012 &ndash; I think like it&rsquo;s going to be an amazing year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/11/26/blog-block/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-26T01:28:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/11/26/blog-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really thought I&rsquo;d have a lot to blog about since this whole week was a
pretty crazy cross country adventure&hellip;but I can&rsquo;t seem to focus on blogging
at the moment.  I don&rsquo;t know if it&rsquo;s just a writer&rsquo;s block thing or what.
Whenever I sit down to write, I keep thinking I&rsquo;m writing out some formal
document and that ends up causing me to keep thinking about it and then I just
stop.  My goal is to blog <em>more</em> now that I&rsquo;m out in LA and I have lots of
friends around the country that will probably be interested in updates.  At
this point, I&rsquo;m not sure what I&rsquo;m going to do.  I thought about just using
Tumblr instead of my own custom WordPress install or I may simply start fresh
with this domain.  I&rsquo;ll definitely find a way to send out updates on my LA
adventure, but it looks like it&rsquo;ll be a little bit longer.</p>

<p>One quick update though &ndash; I did make it to LA just fine and both kitties made
it smoothly.  My furniture isn&rsquo;t here yet, so my apartment is basically empty
at the moment, but at least I&rsquo;m here.  I&rsquo;ll post more in the near future, but
so far, so good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[T-0]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/10/28/t-0/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-28T21:09:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/10/28/t-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is my last day of work on the East Coast. It&rsquo;s a sad day since I&rsquo;m
leaving a stable company full of good people and interesting opportunities. At
the same time, it&rsquo;s an exciting day since I&rsquo;m leaving so I can prepare myself
for the 2200 mile move to Los Angeles before I start my dream job of building
spaceships. I never thought I&rsquo;d be trading my reasonably large house in
Tennessee and basically all of my stuff for a tiny one bedroom apartment in
LA, but I never thought I&rsquo;d be able to work on spaceships either.</p>

<p>I got a great send off from my coworkers. A few of them decided to do a little
decorating to my cube&hellip;</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0017.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0017.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>&hellip;and my car&hellip;</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0024.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0024.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>&hellip;but the best part was the cupcake. :)</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0021.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2011-10-28-t-0/IMG_0021.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alter Oculos - Project #1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/04/14/alter-oculos-project-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T22:23:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/04/14/alter-oculos-project-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few guys I know decided to start a photo group on Flickr called Alter
Oculos. It&rsquo;s a group for sharing photowalk images and trying out some photo
projects as a group. This week, we decided to all use the same set of shots,
but then we&rsquo;ll all process them and compare our take on the post processing.
These are my two finished images. I think the first turned out ok, but I
really like the second image quite a lot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/88578101@N00/5620858228"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5266/5620858228_b9fe1acaa1.jpg" alt="Alter Oculos Post Processing Project #1 - Scene 1" /></a> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/88578101@N00/5620857666"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5147/5620857666_2d56b77f9e.jpg" alt="Alter Oculos Post Processing Project #1 - Scene 2" /></a></p>

<p>The photos were taken by Matthew Osborne &ndash; you can see more of his images
here: <a href="http://www.fli%0Ackr.com/photos/matthewosbornephotography/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewosbornephotography/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goals - 2011 Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/01/03/goals-2011-edition/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-03T20:07:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/01/03/goals-2011-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year, I&rsquo;m setting 5 major goals for myself. I have several other
behaviors to change/actions to take this year, but I&rsquo;m only considering these
five items my goals since they are realistic, actionable, and measurable.</p>

<h3>Release a new app or website</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been working on several ideas over the last year or so and I&rsquo;m going to
really push to get at least one new project released publicly. I&rsquo;m not going
to be more specific other than the new &ldquo;thing&rdquo; will must be something anyone
can sign up for or download. Open source, closed source, free, or paid &ndash;
doesn&rsquo;t matter &ndash; I just want to complete v1.0 of a new project.</p>

<h3>Max out 401K &amp; Roth IRA</h3>

<p>Pretty simple &ndash; $16,500 pre-tax dollars into the 401K and $5,000 of after-tax
dollars into a Roth IRA.</p>

<h3>Lose weight</h3>

<p>Nothing special about this goal. I&rsquo;m targeting 35 pounds lost by the end of
the year. I&rsquo;ve had this one on my goal list for a while, so it&rsquo;s time to
finally knock this one off.</p>

<h3>Write a journal entry a day</h3>

<p>This is a new one for me. I wanted to do a 365 photo project, but I&rsquo;d really
like to do more writing&hellip;so a 365 writing project it is. I won&rsquo;t be
publishing these, but I&rsquo;m really enjoying it so far (even though I&rsquo;m only 3
days in).</p>

<p>2011 feels different from years past, so I have pretty high hopes for
accomplishing these goals (as well as several other things).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Back on 2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/12/28/looking-back-on-2010/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-28T23:57:51-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/12/28/looking-back-on-2010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in January, I posted my [top three goals for
2010.](<a href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/01/10/my-goals-the-2010-edition/">http://www.adambyram.com/2010/01/10/my-goals-the-2010-edition/</a></p>

<p>)</p>

<p>So how did I do? Well&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>Goal: Get Healthy</strong><br/>
Result: Failed &ndash; I totally bombed this one. A lot of changes happened in 2010
that distracted me from this goal. This WILL be happening in 2011.</p>

<p><strong>Goal: Side Income to Livable Levels</strong><br/>
Result: Success / Not Applicable &ndash; This originally came about because I wanted
to leave me previous job and work for myself. I did end up working for myself
anyway, but I didn&rsquo;t get my side income to livable levels. Having said that, I
did start a new job which negated this goal (and resulted in an even better
outcome in a lot of ways). I still love the idea of running my own business
and maybe it&rsquo;ll happen when it&rsquo;s time. I tried to force it this time and that
wasn&rsquo;t the right way to do it. In the meantime, everything is working out
pretty awesomely.</p>

<p><strong>Goal: See a Space Shuttle Launch (in person)</strong><br/>
Result: Success &ndash; I hit a home run on this one. I watched the next to last
launch of Atlantis in May (from Titusville) and then I won the lottery by
being selected for the NASA Tweetup for Discovery&rsquo;s final flight. While I
didn&rsquo;t see Discovery launch (yet &ndash; 2011 goal now), I did get an amazing
experience at NASA including standing just a few hundred yards from Discovery
on the launchpad.</p>

<p>Overall, I&rsquo;m OK with my progress (all things considered). I&rsquo;m disappointed in
myself for not making progress on my &ldquo;Get Healthy&rdquo; goal, but it was a bit of a
crazy year. I&rsquo;m happy with my direction heading into 2011 so 2010 was
definitely not a waste. While I may not have accomplished all of the goals I
wanted, 2011 is looking to be the best year yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NASA Tweetup Preview]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/11/07/nasa-tweetup-preview/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-07T22:19:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/11/07/nasa-tweetup-preview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most of you probably know I just spent a week down at NASA for the STS-133
Tweetup. 150 of us were down there to watch Discovery lift off for her final
flight. It was an amazing trip even though we didn&rsquo;t get to see Discovery
launch (we may get a chance later). I&rsquo;m going to post lots of info about the
trip and my thoughts about it, but I need a bit of time to catch up on things,
process my photos, and generally relax a bit. I&rsquo;ll try to have some info up
late this week, but in the meantime, here are some things to check out:</p>

<p>We have a group setup on Flickr where lots of people are sending Tweetup
photos. If you&rsquo;re curious about the things we saw, take a look here:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/group%0As/sts133tweetup/pool/">http://www.flickr.com/groups/sts133tweetup/pool/</a></p>

<p>If you want to see <em>exactly</em> what we saw, you get watch the Justin.tv stream
of pretty much the whole tweetup right here (note &ndash; lots of videos here&hellip;not
official NASA videos and lots of them are from the parties. I know the actual
tweetup content is in here somewhere though):</p>

<p><a href="http://www.justin.tv/nasatweetup/vid%0Aeos">http://www.justin.tv/nasatweetup/videos</a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all for now. More to come in a couple of days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Camping at Elkmont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/10/24/camping-at-elkmont/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-24T21:47:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/10/24/camping-at-elkmont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was my first time camping at Elkmont. My Dad &amp; I used to go
camping a good bit when I was little, so I thought he would like going camping
in the Smokies. I heard good things about Elkmont and they happened to have a
creekside site available for the weekend, so that&rsquo;s what I reserved.</p>

<p>We arrived around 3pm on Saturday and got checked in pretty fast. Our campsite
was G11 which was just a quick trip down the road from the ranger station. We
had one of the small sites &ndash; just a tent pad, fire ring, a picnic table, and a
single parking spot. The tent went up pretty quickly, so we got small fire
going early in the evening and just sat around the campsite. We ended up
cooking some steaks and potatoes for dinner &ndash; the cooking part went fine, but
we didn&rsquo;t bring quite enough light for the picnic table. We had plenty of
flashlights, but we didn&rsquo;t think we&rsquo;d need a big lantern&hellip;turns out, the
potatoes &amp; steak took longer than we expected and it gets dark early&hellip;so we
basically ate in the dark. We stayed up pretty late (11:30-ish) and then
turned in for the night. We decided to cook some eggs &amp; bacon the following
morning, walked a good bit of the Elkmont site, and then headed out. A few
photos from the trip are here:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fl%0Aickr.com/photos/adambyram/sets/72157625235026618/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/adambyram/sets/72157625235026618/</a></p>

<p>So what did I think? Well&hellip;</p>

<h3>Proximity to other campers</h3>

<p>I was surprised how close we were to other campers. Some of the areas seem to
be spaced out a bit more, but the &ldquo;G&rdquo; section was pretty packed. If you&rsquo;re
wanting to get away from everything, Elkmont may not do it for you. I think
I&rsquo;d like it more with a camper so some of the sounds are muffled. In a tent,
every foot step, car, motorcycle, kid&rsquo;s bike, etc makes quite a bit of noise
and you can&rsquo;t really escape it. Section &ldquo;G&rdquo; also allows generators during the
day, so quite a few sites had those going during the day.</p>

<h3>Pay attention to the rules (i.e. keep food safe)</h3>

<p>We didn&rsquo;t have this problem, but some of our nearby campers did&hellip; The rules
you agree to when you reserve a spot state that you&rsquo;ll keep your food locked
in your car at all times unless you&rsquo;re physically with the food at the site.
Some guys a couple of sites over from us didn&rsquo;t do this and left their cooler
our while they went for a motorcycle ride. Shortly after they left, the
rangers came by and confiscated all of their food (including the cooler
itself). On top of that, anyone caught breaking the rules is fined $75. So if
you camp at Elkmont, read &amp; follow by the rules&hellip;they are serious about them
and they really do patrol frequently to verify compliance.</p>

<h3>Jerks nearby</h3>

<p>So being in close proximity to other campers isn&rsquo;t bad normally &ndash; it&rsquo;s a
little noisier as I mentioned, but nothing too bad&hellip;unless you&rsquo;re camping
next to jerks. I don&rsquo;t know what was up with the people that were right next
to us at G9, but their freaking car alarm went on for minutes at a time FOUR
times during the night. Not right next to each other either &ndash; the first time
was around midnight and they seemed to happen nearly once an hour all the way
up to 3am. At that point, my Dad went over to talk to them and one of the
campers was out trying to quite the truck. I have no idea what was going on,
but a truck alarm blaring at 3am about 100 ft from your head is not awesome.
Another nearby camper told us the following morning that these people had the
alarm go off EIGHT times the night before! If you have great campers nearby,
this will be ok, but since you have no control over who camps next to you, you
should be aware that you too could have a jerk camper during your relaxing
camping experience.</p>

<h3>Overall</h3>

<p>It was a good trip and we&rsquo;ll probably be back to Elkmont in the future. I
didn&rsquo;t really sleep at all due to cars going by (G11 is just across the Little
River from the entrance road to the campground and cars sound pretty loud),
some animal(s) around the campsite overnight (no idea what it was&hellip;but
something was walking around outside for a while late in the night), and the
freaking car alarm. The site was nice in general though and my Dad really
enjoyed it. I think my ideal wilderness retreat would be to go to a secluded
cabin with a great mountain view &amp; an internet connection&hellip;but I can
certainly deal with a regular camping trip every now and then.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to Basics]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/10/22/back-to-basics/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-22T22:29:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/10/22/back-to-basics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you read my blog in the browser and not via RSS, you may notice the look
has changed a bit. Everything is streamlined and I have a more minimalist
style. The blog is back to nice looking, easy to read text with minimal
distractions. I&rsquo;ve decided a lot of things in my life are too cluttered these
days, so I&rsquo;m starting my decluttering right here on the web. In addition to
the style, I&rsquo;ve also simplified the categories on the blog to focus on the
things I really care about &ndash; life, money (personal finance), photography, and
tech. I&rsquo;ll expand those if the need arises, but having the categories this way
seems to give me a little more mental clarity. The RSS feed is also going
through FeedBurner now &ndash; your feed should have automatically swapped over, so
hopefully that won&rsquo;t cause any issues.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also going to start blogging more. I know I&rsquo;ve said that before, but I
mean it this time. I need to work on my writing and now I have more incentive
than normal since I do a good bit of tech writing at work. I can&rsquo;t promise the
topics will always be interesting, but I have a lot of things I want to talk
about. I have quite a few folders of ideas to post, but I have been holding
them because I originally thought I&rsquo;d have a different site for each topic,
but I&rsquo;ve decided against that. It&rsquo;s easier to keep all of the content in one
place and I&rsquo;m more likely to write this way, so we&rsquo;ll see how it goes. More to
come in the near future&hellip;stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 4 - Early Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/06/28/iphone-4-early-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-28T11:19:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/06/28/iphone-4-early-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The main reasons I upgraded from my 3GS to iPhone 4:</p>

<ul>
<li>Retina display</li>
<li>Better battery life</li>
<li>Better camera</li>
</ul>


<h3>Retina</h3>

<p>The display is stunning &ndash; it is crystal clear and the colors are beautiful.
Most apps simply become more crisp (assuming they don&rsquo;t use a lot of low-res
images). I don&rsquo;t think you&rsquo;ll see a ton of difference in the way you use apps
due to the display, but you&rsquo;ll enjoy the experience much more and it&rsquo;ll feel
less like a computer screen. This is one of those things where the old
technology got the job done just fine, but man, after using this display for a
few days now, I can&rsquo;t wait to see it come to iPad and to traditional computer
monitors. Once you get used to retina, all other displays start looking really
blurry.</p>

<h3>Battery Life</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s excellent. It still isn&rsquo;t going to last nearly as long as the iPad, but
it seems to last significantly longer than my 3GS did while performing the
same tasks.</p>

<h3>Camera</h3>

<p>For still photography, the camera seems to be improved, but it&rsquo;s significantly
better at low light photography. This is partly due to the new sensor
technology, but it&rsquo;s also due to the inclusion of a small LED flash. Don&rsquo;t get
me wrong, the low light photos are terrible compared to a DSLR or even a mid-
range Point &amp; Shoot&hellip;but it&rsquo;s a huge step up from the camera in the 3GS that
was barely usable in lower light conditions. Daylight photos (particularly
macro type shots) range from good to excellent. If you want proof, check out
this <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pminton/4740503969/">shot</a> by a friend of
mine. I&rsquo;d say that under optimal conditions, the iPhone 4&rsquo;s still camera is
very competitive with mid-range Point &amp; Shoot cameras. As for video, it&rsquo;s 720p
in size, but don&rsquo;t expect anything close to Bluray quality. I put a couple of
<a href="http://vimeo.com/12805175">videos</a> on my Vimeo account&hellip;these are &ldquo;worst
case&rdquo; shots &ndash; indoors with low light shooting a dark subject with some fast
movement. Quality wise, the video function alone is right there with my
Creative Vado&hellip;there is absolutely no reason to use a Vado, Flip, etc. if you
have an iPhone 4. In fact, when you add on the software (iMovie or otherwise),
the iPhone 4 blows those devices out of the water.</p>

<h3>Overall Feel</h3>

<p>Compared to my 3GS, the iPhone 4 feels better &amp; worse. I love the new design &ndash;
it&rsquo;s more sleek and feels even more solid. The downside is I feel more
paranoid that I&rsquo;m going to drop it. With the 3GS, you could drop it and have a
pretty good chance of only minor scratches or maybe a small crack in the
plastic back. With the iPhone 4, you&rsquo;re either going to damage the glass on
the front or back (and the camera is integrated into that back glass as well)
or you&rsquo;re going to bang up the antennas (since they form the metal band around
the outside). In theory, the glass is super strong and not easy to break, but
something about it just feels a little more fragile. Speed wise, everything
feels fast. If you&rsquo;ve used an iPad, it&rsquo;s pretty much the same. I really don&rsquo;t
notice a ton of speed increase over my 3GS for day to day activities &ndash; I do
know it&rsquo;s much more powerful though, so I&rsquo;m sure future apps will widen this
gap.</p>

<h3>FaceTime</h3>

<p>FaceTime is the video calling feature built-in to each iPhone 4. I tried it
out with a friend from Twitter and it&rsquo;s certainly a nifty feature. It works as
easily as Apple advertises&hellip;call someone, touch a button, and boom &ndash; video
call. The big gotcha (for now) is that both parties must have iPhone 4s AND be
on a WiFi network. I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;ll be using this feature all that much, but
I also prefer e-mail/twitter/IM to phone calls anyway. I can see it being
pretty popular for some people and I do see a few use cases for myself.</p>

<h3>iBooks</h3>

<p>iBooks is an app I use a ton on my iPad. I was hoping the retina display would
make it more readable to me on the iPhone 4. Text &amp; images looks absolutely
fantastic &ndash; but at the end of the day, I just can&rsquo;t read on such a tiny
screen. It&rsquo;s not that the font is too small &ndash; I can see it fine &ndash; I just can&rsquo;t
fit enough content on the screen for my tastes. I read mostly technical (or at
least non-fiction books) though, so books with less structured content may be
a bit better. Imagine reading the tiny bibles you used to find in hotels &ndash;
that&rsquo;s what it&rsquo;s like reading on the iPhone 4&hellip;super crisp text, but a little
bitty reading surface. I do like having the ability to look up something in
iBooks in an emergency though &ndash; so I&rsquo;ll keep it installed just in case.</p>

<h3>Multitasking</h3>

<p>A lot of people have been anxiously awaiting multitasking on iPhone. I&rsquo;m not
one of them. I would like a few apps to be able to update in the background
(Twitter for example) and I&rsquo;d like to have a live IM client, but that&rsquo;s about
it. I don&rsquo;t use Skype or Pandora on the phone, but if I did, I&rsquo;d be happy. For
me, this is a nice feature, but the only real benefit I get is that it&rsquo;s
slightly faster to switch between applications. Maybe I&rsquo;ll be wow&rsquo;d with what
people are able to do with this in the future, but for now, I just don&rsquo;t see
much benefit for the tasks I do today&hellip;but I was never the target of this
feature in the first place.</p>

<h3>Reception</h3>

<p>You&rsquo;ve probably heard about the reception issues with iPhone 4. Steve Jobs
said they don&rsquo;t exist, but if they did, it&rsquo;s because you&rsquo;re holding it the
wrong way. Apple corporate said they exist on all phones and you should buy a
case. Well, they definitely do exist and I&rsquo;m holding my phone the same way
I&rsquo;ve held every Apple iPhone. I&rsquo;m going to end up buying a case I&rsquo;m sure, but
I&rsquo;m really disappointed in Apple over this one. If you hold the phone in your
left hand, you&rsquo;ll connect two of the antennas with your finger or palm. By
doing this, your 5 bars of full signal will drop to &ldquo;No Service&rdquo; within 30
seconds or so unless you happen to be <em>very</em> close to a cell tower. At home, I
can do this easily every time I try. In West Knoxville, I had a harder time
getting the signal to drop&hellip;so it seems to be partially dependent on your
proximity to cell towers. I have yet to have a call drop due to this, but I
have had SMS messages and data downloads stop/fail due to it&hellip;so it isn&rsquo;t
just a display issue &ndash; it really is losing the signal. Apple says some type of
fix is on the way and if that&rsquo;s the case, then maybe this won&rsquo;t be a problem
much longer. I expected I would get better reception than my 3GS due to the
larger exposed antenna, but so far, my 3GS had a more stable signal. Call
quality is as good or better on the iPhone 4 though. I haven&rsquo;t tried making a
call from a noisy area yet, but all of the calls I&rsquo;ve made have sounded very
clear on my end and no complaints from those that I&rsquo;ve called.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giving Tumblr a Try]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/03/14/giving-tumblr-a-try/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-14T06:41:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/03/14/giving-tumblr-a-try</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I don&rsquo;t post very much to this blog&hellip;I never have really. I can&rsquo;t
quite figure out a good use for my domain. I post a reasonable amount on
<a href="http://www.twitter.com/adambyram">Twitter</a> these days, so I thought I&rsquo;d give
<a href="http://www.tumblr.com">Tumblr</a> a try. It&rsquo;s a microblogging site &ndash; there is no
140 character limit like there is on Twitter, but it&rsquo;s setup in a way that
encourages quick, focused posts. I don&rsquo;t know if I&rsquo;ll stay active with it or
not, but since I don&rsquo;t have a good way to integrate my Tumblr posts into this
blog, I wanted to give you guys the direct link for any that are interested in
follow me there. Here&rsquo;s the URL:</p>

<p><a href="http://adambyram.tumblr.com">http://adambyram.tumblr.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FTL is spooled. Jumping in 3... 2... 1...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/02/12/ftl-is-spooled-jumping-in-3-2-1/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-12T09:23:10-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/02/12/ftl-is-spooled-jumping-in-3-2-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JUMP!</p>

<p>Today I resigned from my job at the small software startup.  I&rsquo;m not going to
go into the details as to why I left, but I&rsquo;ll just say that I don&rsquo;t regret
joining the company, but I feel I may have regretted it if I stayed any longer
due to various things (including some opportunities outside of the company).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be posting more about my future plans over at my company blog &ndash;
<a href="http://www.cogitu.com/blog/">http://www.cogitu.com/blog/</a> &ndash; so if you&rsquo;re interested, be sure to check that
out for more details (a post will be up by Monday at the latest).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Goals - The 2010 Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/01/10/my-goals-the-2010-edition/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-10T00:55:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/01/10/my-goals-the-2010-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last year, I&rsquo;ve been making a list of things I want to accomplish (or
at least think about accomplishing) in 2010. Now that 2010 is finally here,
it&rsquo;s time to define my final list of goals. I ended up with 24 goals. It&rsquo;s
unreasonable to think that I could focus on all 24 goals (plus any new ones
that come up during the year), so I&rsquo;m only going to focus on three main goals.
I&rsquo;m not going to ignore my other goals by any means, but these three items are
the places I&rsquo;m going to focus 95% of my energy this year:</p>

<h2>Get healthy</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve learned a lot about healthier eating and exercise over the last year, but
I&rsquo;ve failed at putting it into practice for an extended period of time. I want
to be healthier for quite a few good reasons and it&rsquo;s time I step up and do
it. For this goal, my criteria are that I must be able to sustain the
lifestyle changes and my target weight is 175 (with a stretch goal of 150) by
the end of the year. (I know weight isn&rsquo;t the only thing that makes one
&ldquo;healthy&rdquo;, but I&rsquo;m going to use it as the measurable part of this goal
anyway.)</p>

<h2>Side income to livable levels</h2>

<p>I already make money on the side of my day job, but it&rsquo;s not much&hellip;certainly
nowhere close to anything I can live off. For 2010, my goal is to find a
sustainable way to bring in $2500/mo after taxes. This goal isn&rsquo;t to make that
much on the side <em>each</em> month this year, it&rsquo;s to <em>start</em> doing it so I could
support myself fully in 2011&hellip;a proof of concept essentially. If I can hit
this amount, that works out to around $30K/yr which is all I need to live very
comfortably at this point in my life.</p>

<h2>See a Space Shuttle launch (in person)</h2>

<p>I went to space camp and I love NASA (and space exploration in general), but I
have yet to see a shuttle launch. It&rsquo;s something I&rsquo;ve always wanted to do, but
I&rsquo;ve never made the time. There are only 5 shuttle launches left (as of right
now) and they all happen in 2010. I don&rsquo;t care which launch I see, but I&rsquo;m
going to see one in person (hopefully from the VIP area so I can get a good
view).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
