<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Money | Adam Byram]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/categories/money/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-31T19:13:02-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.adambyram.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Byram]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Countdown to Debt Free]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2008/05/12/countdown-to-debt-free/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-12T07:52:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2008/05/12/countdown-to-debt-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of last month, I paid off my student loans - it was quite hard to
write a $14,000 check, but once it was written, I didn't regret it at all. It
feels great knowing they are out of the way. The only debt I have left at this
point (other than my primary mortgage) is a second mortgage I got when I
bought my house (my down payment didn't go as far as I had hoped due to
closing costs, new house expenses, etc). This one is higher than my student
loans ($18,000), but it's possible that I can knock it out by the end of the
year assuming no major financial issues arise between now and then. I may end
up having to sell some stuff to make this happen, but we'll see how that
goes...I'm willing to do what is needed to take care of business.</p>

<p>This morning I sent in my monthly payment with a nice little $500 additional
principle attached and I'm already starting to feel better. :) Debt free, here
I come!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Top 10 Ways to Save Money]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2007/09/10/my-top-10-ways-to-save-money/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-10T01:23:33-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2007/09/10/my-top-10-ways-to-save-money</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>1) Cut the cable</strong><br/>
Do you really need those 100 channels you never watch?  I have an HDTV that
picks up over the air channels and I can assure you that my FOX, NBC, ABC, and
PBS look just as good, if not better, than anything you would get on cable.
It does mean giving up certain channels (I do miss Sci-Fi, Discovery, and a
couple of other ones), but it saves a ton of money and you don't have to deal
with the cable company.</p>

<p><strong>2) Check the unit price on grocery items</strong><br/>
I find it amazing that identical items in the grocery have vastly different
pricing.  Two different brands of the same pasta sauce may have the same price
per item, but if you look at the unit price, you may see that one of them
actually gives you quite a bit more sauce for the same price (you can't always
tell this by the size of the container).  Another really surprising thing is
that larger "family size" items are often more per unit than the "regular"
size item - sounds strange, but if you check out the unit price on the labels,
you'll see what I'm talking about.</p>

<p><strong>3) Use fans instead of air conditioner when possible</strong><br/>
This certainly depends on where you live, but around here, it's quite hot in
the summer.  If I know I'm only going to be in a couple of rooms in the house,
I'll just open a window or use a fan since there is no point to chilling the
whole house.</p>

<p><strong>4) Never buy on credit (specifically don't pay interest)</strong><br/>
Hopefully it's obvious that it's always worse to end up paying more for an
item than what the store charged...if not, these tips probably won't help...
The best thing you can do for yourself is to stop using credit cards - go with
your bank check card.</p>

<p><strong>5) Minimize impulse buying (still working on this one - but it usually works well with #7)</strong><br/>
This is one of the hardest things for me to do - you see the new gadget come
out, want the extra pack of candy in the grocery that you didn't plan on,
decide it's time to buy an HDTV...  The best way I've found to minimize this
is to keep very little money in my checking account - I move it all to
investments (either mutual funds or savings accounts like ING Direct).  That
way, I can get the money if I need it, but I don't have enough to make a huge
purchase unless I go through a transfer process that takes 3-5 days...by then,
I may decide I didn't really need the item anyway.</p>

<p><strong>6) Know where your money is going / Implement a budget</strong><br/>
It's really important that you know where your money is going - I don't
particularly like doing a true budget, so I track all expenses (including
categories) in Quicken, then review spending each month to see how I'm doing
against my mental budget.  Doing a "real" budget would be more helpful, but I
haven't found a nice way to do the budget the way I want in Quicken.</p>

<p><strong>7) Treat yourself to something nice</strong><br/>
When I first decided I would start cutting my expenses and saving up to pay
off my student loans early, I kept myself from buying anything unless I really
needed it.  The problem I ran into was that sometimes it would feel even worse
than being broke - sometimes you just need to have a little something extra.
I'm taking buying a $50 video game or $100 night out - not buying a car or
something crazy like that.  If you don't treat yourself, what will probably
happen is that you'll eventually break down and spend like crazy for a bit and
it'll put you back to square one - sounds crazy I know, but trust me, it's
better to set aside $100/mo blow money instead of spending $3000 one month
because you couldn't take it anymore.</p>

<p><strong>8) Use utilities efficiently</strong><br/>
Nothing special here - use compact florescent light bulbs, turn off the lights
when you're not in the room, minimize hot water usage, don't water the lawn if
you don't have to, etc.  Turning off the computer at night can save about
$20/mo - you'll be surprised at home much it costs to use different items you
have around the house.</p>

<p><strong>9) Be as frugal as possible, but not cheap (buy good quality / be proactive)</strong><br/>
I'll explain this one via an example - 6 months ago, I bought a little
battery-powered drill for $30.  I used it to drive in some screws here and
there and it worked fine.  I recently decided to put in new cabinets and
needed to do more heavy duty work.  Well, the drill basically bit the dust -
it couldn't take the stress.  So now I need a new drill... If I would have
went ahead and bought a good quality drill from the start for $100 or so, I
would have come out much better than having to go buy a new one now (plus the
time lost messing with the cheap drill trying to finish the job).  These days,
I try to buy the middle priced version of whatever I'm buying - I don't care
for paying premium prices, but I don't mind paying a few dollars more when
those few dollars create enough value to justify the extra expense.</p>

<p><strong>10) Avoid marketing as much as possible</strong><br/>
This sounds dumb, but the more marketing you're exposed to, the more stuff
you'll want to buy - that's the point of marketing after all.  Now that
doesn't mean that you'll buy something just because you saw a single ad, but
it does mean that the more ads you see, the harder #5 gets.  I know I'm going
to have to stay away from Apple keynotes - I don't know why, but they always
make me want to buy the newest thing Apple thought up...so far, I've been able
to resist, but it'd be even better if I would just stop watching...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Money Choices]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2007/07/01/money-choices/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-01T22:39:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2007/07/01/money-choices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I set a goal for myself at the beginning of 2007 - that goal was to be debt
free except the house by the end of the year.  (Yeah - I drank the <a href="http://www.daveramsey.com">Dave
Ramsey kool-aid</a>...well, mostly at least...)  After
the first few months, I figured out how to trim my expenses even more and
figured out that I could actually pay off my student loans by my birthday (end
of September).  At the end of 2006, I paid off all credit cards and any other
foolishness I had - so I only have 3 "debt" items laying around these days:
student loans (~$15K total), 1st mortgage, and 2nd mortgage.</p>

<p>I'm on track to pay off my student loans by the end of September, but it's
really tempting to pay off the 2nd mortgage first.  Both are about the same
amount (second mortgage is a few thousand higher, but that just means waiting
a month or so to pay it off if I chose that route), but the interest rate on
my student loan is 4.25% while the second mortgage is at 8.25%.  Because of
that (and the terms around each loan), my student loan payment is $125 a month
and my 2nd mortgage is $190...so paying it off first would free up $190
instead of only $125.</p>

<p>But here's the catch (and the reason I'll probably still pay off the student
loans first) - in a worst case scenario, I could probably sell the house and
at least break even (if not, I wouldn't owe much).  In that case, both
mortgages would be taken care of, but the student loan will still be there.
No matter what happens (practically...there are a few legal things that I'm
going to ignore), I'm stuck with the student loan for up to 14 more years (the
remaining length of the loan).  It seems really risky to me to pay off the
second mortgage before the student loans.</p>

<p>Realistically, my plan would be to pay off the student loans first (just to
have them out of the way), buy some new camera equipment (as a celebration
type thing...and because I "need" it...), fill up the 5K for Roth IRA 2008,
then focus on knocking out my 2nd mortgage as quickly as possible.  If raises
go as usual next year at work, I can probably expect I would have the income
to do all of the above between now and Jan 1 2009.  It's just a question of
what else will happen between now and then.</p>

<p>Anyway - I'm 80% sure I'm going to go ahead and pay off the student loans as
planned, but it's still a hard choice because of the interest rates (and the
fact that I could invest it and do decently as well).  But when it comes down
to it, I've really liked not having credit card payments and it feels great
not to be paying on my everyday items anymore.  I can only imagine what it
will feel like to have the house paid off one day...  The really amazing thing
is that it's not <em>that</em> hard - oh, it's hard, but not <em>that</em> hard.  At the
very least, it's been interesting having to make all these choices now that I
have a "real world" income.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
