<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tech | Adam Byram]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-17T19:33:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.adambyram.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Byram]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on the 13&quot; MacBook Air]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/05/thoughts-on-the-13-macbook-air/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T21:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/01/05/thoughts-on-the-13-macbook-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've had my 13" MacBook Air (mid-2011 model) for a few weeks now and thought it'd be a good idea to share my impressions.  I originally moved to Apple on a black MacBook, then switched to a top end 17" MacBook Pro, and now I'm on an Air.</p>

<h2>What's Good?</h2>

<p><strong>Weight</strong></p>

<p>It's fantastically light.  My MacBook Pro feels like a brick after using the MBA for a while.</p>

<p><strong>Size</strong></p>

<p>Not only is it light, it's thin.  Like, really thin.  It's not really that much thicker than my iPad and that's impressive when you consider it's a full featured computer.</p>

<p><strong>Battery Life</strong></p>

<p>I haven't used it for photo/video editing nor have I used it for games, so my usage is pretty moderate, but still, the battery life is excellent.  My MacBook Pro has a good battery life for its size, but the Air has been really impressive.  I haven't timed the battery life, but I can say that I frequently use it for extended periods of time without even thinking about the power cable.  That hasn't been my experience with other laptops (Apple or otherwise).</p>

<p><strong>Solid State Drive</strong></p>

<p>It's amazing how much of a difference a solid state drive makes.  Startup is extremely fast, launching apps is even faster, and even development in a virtual machine is faster.</p>

<h2>What's Bad?</h2>

<p><strong>Screen Size</strong></p>

<p>It's totally usable for most of my everyday tasks, but for things like development, it's a bit small.  The good news is that it powers an external monitor just fine.  If you're on the go and need to do certain kinds of tasks, it'll feel a bit cramped.  I can't imagine the MacBook Airs line won't merge with the MacBook Pro line to provide the larger screen sizes in the future.</p>

<h2>Other Thoughts</h2>

<p>That's actually the only negative thing I've noticed.  I happen to have the 4GB RAM/256GB SSD model, so it's maxed out on the basic specs.  It'd be nice if the RAM went up to 8GB, but honestly, 4GB has been plenty (even with large-ish databases loaded) due to the SSD.  The storage space may end up being a problem for me down the road if I started storing my main photo library, but I'm undecided how I want to handle that.  Overall, the MacBook Air is the best laptop I've used for my everyday tasks.  I'm sure I'll find a few things where I miss the power of my PC workstation or my MacBook Pro, but so far, I've really impressed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/switching-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T19:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2011/12/31/switching-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been looking into Octopress for a month or so now and I finally decided to take the plunge.  As of now, this blog is now powered by Octopress (more or less out of the box) instead of WordPress.  I'd like to change the theme a bit, but it's good enough that I'll leave it for now.</p>

<h3>WordPress -> Octopress</h3>

<p>Nothing was wrong with WordPress itself, but I just didn't use any of the features it offered.  I'd rather just type the blog posts in a regular editor instead of a textbox on a webpage.  There are some great tools out there that help with that of course, but I just don't need the features there either.  In addition, maintaining WordPress means logging in pretty often to check for updates, apply them, make sure the database is backed up, etc.  All of that would be just fine if I received enough benefit to offset the time there, but I just didn't.</p>

<h3>Enter Heroku</h3>

<p>In addition to switching the blogging engine, I moved the physical blog from Linode over to Heroku + Amazon S3.  My blog is very low traffic, so I don't need a high powered VPS host that I have to maintain &amp; patch.  Heroku offers a free account if you don't need much power and can live without a database (well, effectively without a DB - a 5MB one is included).  I decided to go ahead and put any post specific images/files onto S3 since Heroku offers a limited amount of local storage and I can also redeploy back to Linode if something doesn't work out at Heroku.  For the record though, I <em>love</em> Linode for a Linux VPS host.  I highly recommend them as long as you're comfortable dealing with Linux via the command line.</p>

<h3>Simplicity</h3>

<p>As I get older, the technology side of things appeals to me less and less.  I still love technology in general, but the nitty gritty details of what platform/framework/OS/whatever is the best is less and less interesting to me.  I'm more interested in the best way to deliver a solution in a way that is as simple as possible.  That doesn't mean I'm adverse to complexity under the hood though. It means I value the experience, productivity, and the ability to simply get things done over the technical aspects of a solution.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 4 - Early Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/06/28/iphone-4-early-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-28T11:19:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/06/28/iphone-4-early-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The main reasons I upgraded from my 3GS to iPhone 4:</p>

<ul>
<li>Retina display</li>
<li>Better battery life</li>
<li>Better camera</li>
</ul>


<h3>Retina</h3>

<p>The display is stunning - it is crystal clear and the colors are beautiful.
Most apps simply become more crisp (assuming they don't use a lot of low-res
images). I don't think you'll see a ton of difference in the way you use apps
due to the display, but you'll enjoy the experience much more and it'll feel
less like a computer screen. This is one of those things where the old
technology got the job done just fine, but man, after using this display for a
few days now, I can't wait to see it come to iPad and to traditional computer
monitors. Once you get used to retina, all other displays start looking really
blurry.</p>

<h3>Battery Life</h3>

<p>It's excellent. It still isn't going to last nearly as long as the iPad, but
it seems to last significantly longer than my 3GS did while performing the
same tasks.</p>

<h3>Camera</h3>

<p>For still photography, the camera seems to be improved, but it's significantly
better at low light photography. This is partly due to the new sensor
technology, but it's also due to the inclusion of a small LED flash. Don't get
me wrong, the low light photos are terrible compared to a DSLR or even a mid-
range Point &amp; Shoot...but it's a huge step up from the camera in the 3GS that
was barely usable in lower light conditions. Daylight photos (particularly
macro type shots) range from good to excellent. If you want proof, check out
this <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pminton/4740503969/">shot</a> by a friend of
mine. I'd say that under optimal conditions, the iPhone 4's still camera is
very competitive with mid-range Point &amp; Shoot cameras. As for video, it's 720p
in size, but don't expect anything close to Bluray quality. I put a couple of
<a href="http://vimeo.com/12805175">videos</a> on my Vimeo account...these are "worst
case" shots - indoors with low light shooting a dark subject with some fast
movement. Quality wise, the video function alone is right there with my
Creative Vado...there is absolutely no reason to use a Vado, Flip, etc. if you
have an iPhone 4. In fact, when you add on the software (iMovie or otherwise),
the iPhone 4 blows those devices out of the water.</p>

<h3>Overall Feel</h3>

<p>Compared to my 3GS, the iPhone 4 feels better &amp; worse. I love the new design -
it's more sleek and feels even more solid. The downside is I feel more
paranoid that I'm going to drop it. With the 3GS, you could drop it and have a
pretty good chance of only minor scratches or maybe a small crack in the
plastic back. With the iPhone 4, you're either going to damage the glass on
the front or back (and the camera is integrated into that back glass as well)
or you're going to bang up the antennas (since they form the metal band around
the outside). In theory, the glass is super strong and not easy to break, but
something about it just feels a little more fragile. Speed wise, everything
feels fast. If you've used an iPad, it's pretty much the same. I really don't
notice a ton of speed increase over my 3GS for day to day activities - I do
know it's much more powerful though, so I'm sure future apps will widen this
gap.</p>

<h3>FaceTime</h3>

<p>FaceTime is the video calling feature built-in to each iPhone 4. I tried it
out with a friend from Twitter and it's certainly a nifty feature. It works as
easily as Apple advertises...call someone, touch a button, and boom - video
call. The big gotcha (for now) is that both parties must have iPhone 4s AND be
on a WiFi network. I'm not sure I'll be using this feature all that much, but
I also prefer e-mail/twitter/IM to phone calls anyway. I can see it being
pretty popular for some people and I do see a few use cases for myself.</p>

<h3>iBooks</h3>

<p>iBooks is an app I use a ton on my iPad. I was hoping the retina display would
make it more readable to me on the iPhone 4. Text &amp; images looks absolutely
fantastic - but at the end of the day, I just can't read on such a tiny
screen. It's not that the font is too small - I can see it fine - I just can't
fit enough content on the screen for my tastes. I read mostly technical (or at
least non-fiction books) though, so books with less structured content may be
a bit better. Imagine reading the tiny bibles you used to find in hotels -
that's what it's like reading on the iPhone 4...super crisp text, but a little
bitty reading surface. I do like having the ability to look up something in
iBooks in an emergency though - so I'll keep it installed just in case.</p>

<h3>Multitasking</h3>

<p>A lot of people have been anxiously awaiting multitasking on iPhone. I'm not
one of them. I would like a few apps to be able to update in the background
(Twitter for example) and I'd like to have a live IM client, but that's about
it. I don't use Skype or Pandora on the phone, but if I did, I'd be happy. For
me, this is a nice feature, but the only real benefit I get is that it's
slightly faster to switch between applications. Maybe I'll be wow'd with what
people are able to do with this in the future, but for now, I just don't see
much benefit for the tasks I do today...but I was never the target of this
feature in the first place.</p>

<h3>Reception</h3>

<p>You've probably heard about the reception issues with iPhone 4. Steve Jobs
said they don't exist, but if they did, it's because you're holding it the
wrong way. Apple corporate said they exist on all phones and you should buy a
case. Well, they definitely do exist and I'm holding my phone the same way
I've held every Apple iPhone. I'm going to end up buying a case I'm sure, but
I'm really disappointed in Apple over this one. If you hold the phone in your
left hand, you'll connect two of the antennas with your finger or palm. By
doing this, your 5 bars of full signal will drop to "No Service" within 30
seconds or so unless you happen to be <em>very</em> close to a cell tower. At home, I
can do this easily every time I try. In West Knoxville, I had a harder time
getting the signal to drop...so it seems to be partially dependent on your
proximity to cell towers. I have yet to have a call drop due to this, but I
have had SMS messages and data downloads stop/fail due to it...so it isn't
just a display issue - it really is losing the signal. Apple says some type of
fix is on the way and if that's the case, then maybe this won't be a problem
much longer. I expected I would get better reception than my 3GS due to the
larger exposed antenna, but so far, my 3GS had a more stable signal. Call
quality is as good or better on the iPhone 4 though. I haven't tried making a
call from a noisy area yet, but all of the calls I've made have sounded very
clear on my end and no complaints from those that I've called.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giving Tumblr a Try]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2010/03/14/giving-tumblr-a-try/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-14T06:41:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2010/03/14/giving-tumblr-a-try</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I don't post very much to this blog...I never have really. I can't
quite figure out a good use for my domain. I post a reasonable amount on
<a href="http://www.twitter.com/adambyram">Twitter</a> these days, so I thought I'd give
<a href="http://www.tumblr.com">Tumblr</a> a try. It's a microblogging site - there is no
140 character limit like there is on Twitter, but it's setup in a way that
encourages quick, focused posts. I don't know if I'll stay active with it or
not, but since I don't have a good way to integrate my Tumblr posts into this
blog, I wanted to give you guys the direct link for any that are interested in
follow me there. Here's the URL:</p>

<p><a href="http://adambyram.tumblr.com">http://adambyram.tumblr.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My AT&T U-verse Experience in Knoxville]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2009/10/28/my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-28T13:01:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2009/10/28/my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've had quite a few people ask about my recent AT&amp;T U-verse install, so I
thought a quick blog post was in order. Keep in mind, my install happened
during the first week of the Knoxville, TN U-verse rollout - so I'm sure
things will go faster (as far as the installation goes) as they do more and
more installs in this area.</p>

<p>I chose to go with U-verse because I live in an older neighborhood in
Knoxville and my high speed internet choices are fairly limited. I've had
3Mbps DSL from AT&amp;T for the last 3 years and it's been decent, but I really
needed more upload speed. I'm a software developer so I usually have lots of
large software updates I need to download quite often and I frequently have
fairly large chunks of data I need to upload to a server on a regular basis
(Dropbox, Subversion, etc.). I ended up going with AT&amp;T U-verse since they
offer a package with 18Mbps download and 2Mbps upload...this was my main
consideration for choosing U-verse, not the VoIP service nor the TV service. I
want to make it clear that I didn't compare the TV and phone services to other
providers...so if that is your main focus, this writeup may not be useful to
you.</p>

<p><strong>Speed Test - Before &amp; After</strong> <em>All tests were performed with www.speedtest.net on a MacBook running Snow Leopard connected to my wireless LAN - this is my most common usage scenario, so it's what I decided to test with.  Also, ignore the "distance" in these speed tests...all were performed in Knoxville at the same location.</em></p>

<p>Before U-verse - Speed Test</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2009-10-28-my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/SpeedTest-DSL.png"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2009-10-28-my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/SpeedTest-DSL.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>After U-verse - Speed Test</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2009-10-28-my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/SpeedTest-Uverse.png"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2009-10-28-my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/SpeedTest-Uverse.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>From this quick test, you can see my download rate is much higher, but my
upload rate also got a massive improvement.  The ping time got cut in half as
well - so it's a win-win-win with the U-verse upgrade.  The thing is, the
download rate isn't anywhere near the max rate of 18Mbps, so I decided to try
a speed test against the Atlanta, GA data center since I would assume they
have more capacity than Morristown...</p>

<p>Speed Test - Atlanta</p>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2009-10-28-my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/SpeedTest-Uverse2.png"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2009-10-28-my-att-u-verse-experience-in-knoxville/SpeedTest-Uverse2.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Nice huh?  That's quite close to the max download rate and a very respectable
upload speed...and the ping is lower still.  So the bottom line is U-verse
blows regular DSL out of the water and it is generally better than cable or at
least very comparable.  One of the things I don't like about cable internet is
they use different methods to boost your speeds for short periods of time.  So
you may have a 12Mbps package and for 30 secs - 2 minutes, you may get that
speed when starting a download, but if you're downloading something large, you
will usually notice your download speed dialing back pretty
drastically...whereas I should (in theory) have these U-verse speeds
throughout the whole download.  Realistically though, you're going to be very
unlikely to find a single server that can provide you with a download at these
rates, so the only way you would be able to get this much data flowing would
be to have quite a few downloads going on simultaneously.</p>

<p><strong>The Installation</strong><br/>
Now that the speed test is out of the way, you may want to know about the
installation process.  When I signed up for the install, I was told the
install takes between 4 to 6 hours depending on the services I wanted
installed and the specifics of my house/neighborhood.  The U-verse install
requires two different groups - one is an external group that hooks up your
new equipment on the outside of your house and the other group does everything
inside the house.  In my case, I heard from both groups at 9am - both called
to confirm the appointment and to let me know they were on the way.  The
external guy got here around 9:30am and he started checking the lines outside
my house.  The internal guys got here around 9:45am and I gave them a quick
tour of the places I wanted U-verse.  The external guy worked until 11 or a
little after getting everything prepped and getting some electronics added on
to my house that connect back up to the utility pole.  While he was doing
that, the internal guys explored the attic and crawlspace to determine the
best way to run my new wires.</p>

<p>I have an older house and even though I did have coax cables in most of the
rooms, the cables were always on the opposite wall from my TVs (I have not had
cable for over 3 years...so placement in relation to the cables wasn't exactly
important prior to today).  After talking to the U-verse guys about this, they
agreed they should go ahead and run new wires to all of my TVs...but here's
the awesome part: they ran Cat 5e cables to all my rooms <em>for free</em> instead of
coax!  That was a HUGE win for me...why?  Because now I can add a network
switch in any room with one of the new network jacks and I've got a way to
hardwire in my other goodies...specifically, my Xbox 360 and my Blu-ray
players.  If you already had coax cable that was close to your TVs, I don't
think they would run anything for you since they prefer to use existing
wiring.  Even if they do run new stuff for your install, <em>you</em> must ask for
Cat 5e instead of coax if that is what you want.  They can install either one
usually unless there are specific environmental conditions at your location -
in which case they may not give you a choice.  Anyway, it took them maybe an
hour to hour and a half to run the network drops (I had four sets total in my
case...all from the crawlspace).</p>

<p>By this time, the outside stuff was done and tested.  Both teams must test the
line once it's ready to go - until that point, you don't really know whether
you can actually get U-verse service or not.  If you can't, I don't know what
happens...in my case, both teams agreed that I had an excellent signal here so
we could proceed with installation of the Residential Gateway (the "RG").  So,
they finished up all of the network jacks (adding faceplates, etc.) and then
connected up the RG and the backup battery (a small Belkin UPS...keeps the net
and VoIP up for 4 hours if the power goes out).  The RG essentially <em>IS</em> the
U-verse service...it controls everything.  It has a router (wired and
wireless...b/g only), the VoIP system, and the TV connections.  So if this box
isn't happy, nothing is going to work.  It's important to note that this RG
box needs a true, three prong grounded electrical outlet...I have a 50 year
old home, but luckily a handful of my outlets were updated to be grounded just
before I bought this house.  If you're thinking about U-verse and you have an
older house, make sure you have one of these outlets or you won't be able to
install...you can't use an adapter for this part, you <em>must</em> have a real
grounded outlet near the RG.</p>

<p>As luck would have it, my RG was not happy.  No matter what they did, it just
wouldn't connect to the network.  The techs tried everything they could think
of, but after about 2 hours of troubleshooting it, they decided it we should
try another RG.  At this point, the installation was crossing the 7 hour mark
(the guys didn't even take a lunch break...).  This time, the RG connected
properly.  Even when the RG works, the initial setup still takes about 15
minutes while it configures itself.  Once that was done, I had to connect to
the RG from my MacBook and finish a few last steps on the AT&amp;T website.  Once
all of that was out of the way, the techs connected up all of my TV boxes and
let them sync.  All of them had to perform an automatic update that took
another 10-15 minutes to complete.  Finally, we did a quick test of my phone
system, finished porting my number to the new system, and then they gave me a
quick tour of the U-verse software on the DVR.  It was 6:30pm and the
installation was completed.</p>

<p><strong>So, was it worth it?</strong><br/>
I've had the service for less than a day as I write this, but I can say that
this was 110% worth it for my purposes.  Heck, just getting these great upload
and download rates makes it worth it for me, but getting my house wired with a
wired gigabit network was an unbelievable bonus.  Will I watch all 450+ TV
channels?  No, I'll probably watch 20 or less any given week.  If you like TV
though, this package has as much as any of them.  I don't use the landline
phone much, so I'm not sure how useful the VoIP upgrade will be...call quality
sounds much better (I had some noise prior to this upgrade), but I wanted to
keep my Knoxville number, so I kept the phone service for the moment.  I think
a typical install in a newer home that already had existing coax (or ethernet)
cable in all the right places would be much, much shorter than my
install...maybe 2-4 hours.  So if you're thinking about getting U-verse, don't
let the length of my install deter you - it's very unlikely it'll take longer
than 6 hours max.  All of the guys I dealt with during the install were a
pleasure to work with - other than the technical issues with the bad RG
hardware, everything went as smoothly as one would want.  The real question is
the long term support - will AT&amp;T keep up the great customer service I
experienced or will they drop the ball now that I'm committed to U-verse?
Only time will tell, but I can certainly recommend U-verse at this point.</p>

<p>UPDATE (10/30/2009): It's been a couple of days now and I'm still very happy
with the service.  The only "issue" I've found is that I misunderstood the
stream limit with U-verse as far as TV programming.  I thought all boxes would
be able to watch any channel (HD or SD) and the DVR box could do 4 channels
(all recording or watching 1 and recording 3).  What I didn't realize was that
your entire U-verse system can only support 4 channels simultaneously and of
those 4, only 2 can be HD.  So if you have three boxes like I do, you can't
watch live HD content on all three boxes at the same time unless you're
watching the same show(s) on two or more of the boxes.  If you have lots of
TVs in your house, you may hit this issue pretty quickly.  In my case, I hit
the issue because three of the shows I like to watch come on at the same time
on the same day of the week...when I tried to set the DVR to record all of
them in HD, it told me I couldn't.  I can drop one of the shows down to SD and
it's fine, but while the recording is going on, I won't be able to watch any
other channels in HD (it gives you a blue screen and tells you no more HD
channels can be used until the recording has stopped).  For me, this isn't a
deal breaker, but I thought I should put a note on here since this limit
wasn't clear to me...I knew the limit of 4 streams on the DVR box, I just
didn't realize that was a limit on the whole U-verse install.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
