<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: catfeeder | Adam Byram]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/categories/catfeeder/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-03T09:35:59-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.adambyram.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Byram]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cat Feeder Project - Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/21/cat-feeder-project-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T14:47:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/21/cat-feeder-project-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent some time this weekend working on the hardware to provide cooling for the cat feeder.  The goal is to get the cat feeder to the same temperatures as a refridgerator.  I want to keep the unit as trouble free and cost effective as possible, so I don&rsquo;t want to go the compressor route.  The option I&rsquo;m prototyping is using a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermoelectric_cooling">thermoelectric cooling (TEC)</a> chip (known as a Peltier element).  If you apply power to a TEC, it will cool on one side and heat on another.  If you&rsquo;re trying to cool, you have to remove the heat from the hot side of the TEC with an external heatsink.  TECs are very inefficient, but they should be able to do exactly what I need for this project.</p>

<h2>The Prototype Setup</h2>

<p><a href="http://share.adambyram.com/2012-10-21-cat-feeder-project-part-2/Cooling-Test.jpg"><img src="http://share.adambyram.com/2012-10-21-cat-feeder-project-part-2/Cooling-Test.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h3>Components</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/50">Arduino Uno R3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/184">Adafruit Adjustable Breadboard Power Supply</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/798">12V 1A Regulated Power Adapter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10213">2 x N-Channel MOSFET 60V 30A</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10686">70mm Heatsink and Fan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10080">40mm x 40mm Peltier element</a></li>
<li>Breadboards, jumper wires, heatsink compound, and a few push buttons</li>
</ul>


<h3>Assembly</h3>

<p>I used a few push buttons on the breadboard next the to Arduino so I could control the power to the heatsink&rsquo;s fan and the TEC.  The Arudino&rsquo;s PWM output is sent to the two MOSFETs which varies the amount of current sent to the fan &amp; TEC.  The fan &amp; TEC are both connected to the 12V 1A regulated power supply via the Adafruit breadboard power supply.  I originally tried to run the TEC at a lower voltage than 12V by using the adjustable power supply, but it turned out to be easier to just hook both items directly to the 12V supply.</p>

<h3>Results</h3>

<p>The power supply can&rsquo;t provide enough power to run the TEC with the MOSFET wide open.  One the TEC starts drawing a reasonable amount of power, the fan starts slowing down and evetually, the TEC will draw so much current that everything else shuts down.  I was able to run the fan with the MOSFET wide open and the TEC MOSFET set to about 67% power.  At those settings, the fan runs (at less than full speed) and the TEC is able to cool quite reasonably.  The TEC MOSFET started getting quite hot, so I added a passive heatsink on there.</p>

<p>The at the end of the day, I was able to use the settings above to take the TEC from 75F down to 38F in just a few seconds.  I ran the whole setup in this configuration for about 5 minutes with no issues.  Overall, I&rsquo;m very happy to get near freezing temperatures with the relatively small power supply.</p>

<h3>Next Steps</h3>

<p>I want to get a bigger power supply.  I&rsquo;d really like to get an adjustable lab power supply so I could try different amounts of current to see what exactly I need, but I&rsquo;m thinking I&rsquo;ll try a 12V 2A power supply.  I need to see how much current I can run through the jumper wires if I upgrade the power.  The current test didn&rsquo;t get the wires hot, but I&rsquo;m not sure how much more current they&rsquo;ll take.</p>

<p>At this point, I just need to get the TEC a little cooler while getting the fan to run faster on the heatsink.  I&rsquo;m not too worried about the hinksink though&hellip;it never got that hot even with the fan running slower.  I&rsquo;d like to build a small enclosure so I can experiment with cooling air and not just the surface of the TEC.  This will probably mean I end up building a styrofoam box (or buying one) and mounting a heatsink &amp; fan on the cold side of the TEC to distribute the cooling power.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cat Feeder Project - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/12/cat-feeder-project-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-12T23:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.adambyram.com/2012/10/12/cat-feeder-project-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some of you may know my cat situation.  If you&rsquo;re not aware, the long and the short of it is that my cats used to only eat dry cat food.  One of the cats ended up getting very sick when I moved to Los Angeles.  After she recovered (she&rsquo;s fine now), she decided she&rsquo;ll never eat dry food again and only eats very specific wet cat food.</p>

<p>The problem is that I have two very nice automated dry food feeders that I can&rsquo;t use.  Both cats need to be on a schedule to help control their weight.  So I started researching wet cat food feeders and it turns out, there aren&rsquo;t many.  Not only that, the feeders that are out there all use ice packs which limit you to 8 or maybe 12 hours of feeding.  That&rsquo;s totally not acceptable to me so I&rsquo;ve decided I&rsquo;m going to try to design my own wet cat food feeder.</p>

<h3>What</h3>

<p>So what is this thing?  Well, it&rsquo;s a small (~2 ft wide) unit that has a certain number of rotating food cups.  The food cups can be filled with wet food (or dry food) and the unit can be programmed to expose each food cup to the cats on a specific schedule.  The unexposed food will stay seal up inside the unit and a cooling unit will keep the unexposed food nice and cool.</p>

<p>The goal is to have the unit keep food at refridgerated temperatures (TBD what that means) consistently to allow food to be stored in the unit for up to three days.  That seems to be the maximum time wet food is allowed to be refridgerated based on manufacturer information, so that&rsquo;ll be the target for version 1.</p>

<p>If the machine can feed twice a day for an overnight trip or once a day for a long weekend trip, it&rsquo;ll be fantastic, so that&rsquo;s the target.</p>

<h3>Why</h3>

<p>On top of the issues mentioned above, I really want a exposure to the hardware + software world.  I&rsquo;ve worked on software for quite a long time and basically everything I&rsquo;ve built is totally virtual in nature.  That&rsquo;s all fine and good, but I&rsquo;m really wanting build something physical.  Of course, some software will still be needed, but I&rsquo;ll also get some electrical engineering, product design, and CAD modeling.</p>

<p>The other part of the why is that I really want to be able to go on a long weekend trip and not have to worry about the cats getting fed.  Today, we basically can&rsquo;t be gone for longer than about 8 hours at a time without having someone come by to feed the cats.</p>

<h3>How</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m planning on building everything with some pretty common parts.  The initial design / prototype is going to be all plastic, mainly because I&rsquo;m getting a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/2105227104/ultra-bot-3d-printer">3D printer</a> in December.  The general electronics won&rsquo;t be anything super special.  For the prototype, I&rsquo;ll be using an Arduino Uno for overall control, a motor controller board to rotate the food dish, a external power module to power the cooling system, and a few other random bits.</p>

<p>For cooling, I&rsquo;m planning on using a Peltier cooler.  They aren&rsquo;t very efficient, but they are relatively easy to use and they can work reasonably well (based on my experience with a little mini fridge).  They are also pretty cheap, so it&rsquo;s quite cost effective from a component perspective.  The cooling will be the trickiest aspect of the whole project.</p>

<h3>When</h3>

<p>Well, I&rsquo;ve already started playing with the basic components and working on the hardware design (the body of the feeder, not the electronic components).  The 3D printer won&rsquo;t be available until later in December, so I can&rsquo;t start working on the real prototype until then, but I&rsquo;ll be able to play with the cooling system this month and into November.  My goal is to have a really rough 3D model ready by the time the printer is available.  I&rsquo;m assuming I&rsquo;ll needed lots of revisions to the plastic parts since all of this (the design process, printing process, and design software) is new to me, but I want to be able to hit the ground running.</p>

<p>As far as the finished product, I&rsquo;m hoping to have a totally working prototype in Q1 2013.  Will that happen? I have no idea, but I really, really want this product so I&rsquo;d like to have something working sooner rather than later.</p>

<h3>What&rsquo;s Next</h3>

<p>I plan to blog my progress on this project.  It&rsquo;s as much for me to keep track of things as it is for everyone else to follow along.  Next time, I&rsquo;ll show the current stage of the design and share some thoughts on the design process as well as the design software I&rsquo;m using.  This should be a fun project, so I hope you have as much fun following along as I&rsquo;m having building this thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
